<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VE-Gaia on VE-Gaia: Tackling Climate Change</title>
    <link>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VE-Gaia on VE-Gaia: Tackling Climate Change</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bioclimatic Analysis</title>
      <link>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/bioclimaticanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/bioclimaticanalysis/</guid>
      <description>Bioclimatic analysis is using an understanding of climate to inform building design strategy.Bioclimatic analysis The Ashrae 90.1 climate classes are based around the Koeppen-Geiger classification system, but provide better definition in temperate and maritime zones. See also Koeppen Geiger and Kottek, Greiser,Beck, Rudolf and Rubel. Both the climate zone defined by ASHRAE and the climate zone calculated from the assigned weather data are displayed. The analysis in this report is based on the calculated climate zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Metrics</title>
      <link>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/buildingmetrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/buildingmetrics/</guid>
      <description>Create and understand the building model&amp;rsquo;s geometry.Report format The report has the following features:
 Building type; Building use; Building dimensions;     Building Form;      Building Metrics Report
Notes 1. Dominant heat exchange Buildings are often described as either envelope (skin) or internally loaded; these descriptions characterise the dominant heat exchange in the building.
Skin load dominated means that internal gains are low relative to fabric heat transfers Internal load dominated means that internal gains are high relative to fabric heat transfers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Metrics</title>
      <link>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/climatemetrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/climatemetrics/</guid>
      <description>The climate report provides the headlines you need to know about the weather file you have selected. The Ashrae 90.1 climate classes are based around the Koeppen-Geiger classification system, but provide better definition in temperate and maritime zones. See also Koeppen Geiger and Kottek, Greiser,Beck, Rudolf and Rubel. Both the climate zone defined by ASHRAE and the climate zone calculated from the assigned weather data are displayed. The analysis in this report is based on the calculated climate zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CO2 &amp; Energy</title>
      <link>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/energy/</guid>
      <description>The results in this report are generated by the IES ApacheSim module. ApacheSim is a rigorous building thermal simulation approach that conforms to ANSI/ASHRAE Standard 140. If you wish to know more about ApacheSim and obtain a copy of the ANSI/ASHRAE 140 standard report then visit iesve.comReport format The energy report has the following features:
 Energy/CO2 summary Simulation history Analysis details Annual building energy use Carbon emissions Occupant comfort Peak room loads System loads Room heating loads Room cooling loads  Energy report</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Construction Materials</title>
      <link>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/constructions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/constructions/</guid>
      <description>This review provides a simple summary of the materials utilised in the project model.Report format The report has the following features:
 Total weight of construction materials; List of constructions by weight and volume; Predominant materials in the project  constructions report
Overview. The review highlights the types of materials that are predominant in the project so that alternatives can be considered where possible Generally materials which are dense / heavy, materials that have been heavily processed and materials that have been transported long distances have high embodied energy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural resources </title>
      <link>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/resources/</guid>
      <description>The Natural resources report provides an initial indication of the potential for the energy and rainwater resource available using the selected weather file.Report format The renewables report has the following sections:
 Natural resource summary Baseline figures used Annual solar resource Annual wind resource Annual rainfall figures Analysis details  Natural Resources Report
Notes   In the instance of solar and rainfall resources the baseline collection area has been limited to a practical maximum area equal to the building roof area</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renewable Energy Use</title>
      <link>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/renewables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/renewables/</guid>
      <description>The LZCT review provides an initial indication of the potential for carbon reduction using low or zero carbon technologies.Report format The Renewables report has the following sections:
 Building Summary; Carbon reduction review; Annual carbon emission analysis; Baseline energy; Reduction potential; Baseline emissions; Other analysis comments.  Renewables report
Use the energy hierarchy  Be Lean (reduce) Be Green (renewables) Be Clean (efficient supplies)  Low carbon v renewables Low carbon technologies e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water</title>
      <link>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/water/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/water/</guid>
      <description>The water review provides an initial indication of the potential for water reduction.Report format The water review has the following sections:
 Summary; Baseline Design; Poposed Design; Annual Baseline Consumption; Proposed building Baseline Consumption; Notes; Analysis Details.  Water review
What is water stress? Simply when demand is higher than supply. Lack of supply can be climate, economic or quality driven See - International Water Management Institute and World Water Council for more information::</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
