<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VE-Gaia Reports on VE-Gaia: Tackling Climate Change</title>
    <link>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VE-Gaia Reports on VE-Gaia: Tackling Climate Change</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bioclimatic Analysis</title>
      <link>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/bioclimaticanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/bioclimaticanalysis/</guid>
      <description>Bioclimatic analysis is using an understanding of climate to inform building design strategy.Bioclimatic analysis The Ashrae 90.1 climate classes are based around the Koeppen-Geiger classification system, but provide better definition in temperate and maritime zones. See also Koeppen Geiger and Kottek, Greiser,Beck, Rudolf and Rubel. Both the climate zone defined by ASHRAE and the climate zone calculated from the assigned weather data are displayed. The analysis in this report is based on the calculated climate zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Metrics</title>
      <link>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/buildingmetrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/buildingmetrics/</guid>
      <description>Create and understand the building model&amp;rsquo;s geometry.1. Dominant heat exchange Buildings are often described as either envelope (skin) or internally loaded; these descriptions characterise the dominant heat exchange in the building.
Skin load dominated means that internal gains are low relative to fabric heat transfers Internal load dominated means that internal gains are high relative to fabric heat transfers
So &amp;hellip;
 Skin load dominated = gains &amp;lt; losses  Internal load dominated = gains &amp;gt;= losses  Where:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Metrics</title>
      <link>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/climatemetrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/climatemetrics/</guid>
      <description>The climate report provides the headlines you need to know about the weather file you have selected.1. The Ashrae 90.1 climate classes are based around the Koeppen-Geiger classification system, but provide better definition in temperate and maritime zones. See also Koeppen Geiger and Kottek, Greiser,Beck, Rudolf and Rubel. Both the climate zone defined by ASHRAE and the climate zone calculated from the assigned weather data are displayed. The analysis in this report is based on the calculated climate zone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CO2 &amp; Energy</title>
      <link>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/energy/</guid>
      <description>The results in this report are generated by the IES ApacheSim module. ApacheSim is a rigorous building thermal simulation approach that conforms to ANSI/ASHRAE Standard 140. If you wish to know more about ApacheSim and obtain a copy of the ANSI/ASHRAE 140 standard report then visit iesve.comDetails notes:  PPD is the Predicted Percentage Dissatisfied. This value represents the percentage of people that will find the room thermally uncomfortable. ASHRAE 55 states comfort lies between 5 and 10% PPD (US Only)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Construction Materials</title>
      <link>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/constructions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/constructions/</guid>
      <description>This review provides a simple summary of the materials utilised in the project model.1. The review highlights the types of materials that are predominant in the project so that alternatives can be considered where possible Generally materials which are dense / heavy, materials that have been heavily processed and materials that have been transported long distances have high embodied energy
Additionally some materials contain or are manufactured using substances which are toxic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural resources </title>
      <link>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/resources/</guid>
      <description>The Natural resources report provides an initial indication of the potential for the energy and rainwater resource available using the selected weather file.  In the instance of solar and rainfall resources the baseline collection area has been limited to a practical maximum area equal to the building roof area
  To review Natural Resources this report provides a context based upon an estimate of the building monthly consumption data from your model assuming reasonable simple assumptions</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renewable Energy Use</title>
      <link>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/renewables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/renewables/</guid>
      <description>The LZCT review provides an initial indication of the potential for carbon reduction using low or zero carbon technologies.Use the energy hierarchy  Be Lean (reduce) Be Green (renewables) Be Clean (efficient supplies)  Low carbon v renewables Low carbon technologies e.g. CHP could deliver a better overall result than renewables in many real situations. The review highlights the carbon and energy headlines in the model data because they tell different sides of the story</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water</title>
      <link>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/water/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daveies.github.io/ve-gaia/reports/water/</guid>
      <description>The water review provides an initial indication of the potential for water reduction.What is water stress? Simply when demand is higher than supply. Lack of supply can be climate, economic or quality driven See - International Water Management Institute and World Water Council for more information::
 www.iwmi.cgiar.org/ www.worldwatercouncil.org/index.php?id=25  Considerations Building water use is only part of the water cycle story; for every unit of water used in buildings there are significant distribution losses plus the energy in extraction, processing and distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
